Hi, in previous lesson you have learned what is custom instructions in Visual Studio code and of course compiled and
You also learn the zero three type of instructions. There is a single
Copilot instructions file which a general and apply it to your workspace. There is instructions.md files
Which are applied for specific task of files and there is of course an ancient?
dot md file which is experimental. So we will cover
first two
Instruction files and I will show you how to apply them in
Visual Studio code
Let's open our Visual Studio code, but before if you like a simple
simple
Opportunity to generate instructions. I will show you it
So if you have already a project, if it's small or big project
So you can generate based on your project. Oh
Any I will analyze your project will see how you write code how you'll write this how you'll structure
I have files how your name files and you generate a custom instructions for you
to do it
you need to see
The agent chat and then click on this configure chat icon and click generate agent instructions
So it will start generating instructions. It will analyze your code base and generate
Copilot instructions dot md file
so
And you can see
It considered different
Source was a research. Okay, it already created file
We use all the instructions. So we can
Yeah, it's still generating it
Now we can see
What it is
You have those document provide essential context for your agents working in this conveys
This is the direct application built in with focusing on modern direct practices with a minimum of the
There is a library in the versions. We use there are some component structure
How we store and where we store the components
As there are also some commands
We use to build run review the project
There is also some file organization rule
A really simple like really generic here
There is some code file external dependent dependent is okay internal points like
The files but I would say it's not really
It sounds really easy and not much useful information
So but if you have a bigger project with more files with
More code base as then it can generate generate use some some more relevant
So I will keep it for now
And I will switch to
Browser documentation and I will show you three simple examples of
Guidelines
Of the first example is really general is
About the naming convention rules
And about a rough hand in it really simple example
So for example we can copy it and apply instead of our example
Like I would like to name components name variables and etc
And how we want to handle in the rows
So
This is a general file
But now I want to show you how to use
Specific files like the difference between as this file is applied for all the patterns
And it's a general one and
This files will be applied for some specific needs like especially this one is for types creep and react
Files and the next file is only for documentation files with extension dot empty
So I suggest you create a few
files
Well, let's first find an instruction about to create them. So we need to create dot instructions dot empty files
But I know that you need to create them under dot hit hop folder
And you need to just name your folder as instructions
And then you can name your files like for example
React dot instructions dot MD
This is the instructions for act files
And now I will go to paste the instructions for documents files
So I will create docs dot instructions dot MD
Okay, now we have specific files
So we have clear real drag instructions and clearly document instructions
It's useful when you want to have separate instructions for example
For test for styles
Everything and you shouldn't keep it in one file. You can keep it in separate files
And normally when you view ask a request
Update styles for me or updates the documentation. It should apply and use as resources as the right
instructions filed. We can check we can go to settings
Need to type instructions
Even see there are instructions file locations that you can specify instruction files like we did
And they can be attached in chat
And this files should be under instructions folder because you see dot hit hop slash instructions
And in this folder this all the files are placed
Okay